akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
Kakashi: Shadow of the Anbu
Squad Seven
このたび　おぬしに
担当してもらう下忍たちじゃが。
Regarding the next group of genin
that you'll be in charge of...
（カカシ）また俺にですか？
Me? Again?
そう　嫌な顔をするな。
Now don't look so upset.
ガイは　すでに下忍たちと
班を組んで　任務にも出ている。
Guy has already formed his squad
and has gone out on missions
with them.
おぬしも早く弟子と
任務に出たいと思わんのか。
Aren't you eager to set out with
your own apprentices?
はぁ。
Well...
まあ　よい。
今度の下忍たちには→
I'm sure this new batch of genin
will hold your interest.
少なからず
おぬしも興味を持つじゃろう。
（カカシ）ここは。
Where are we?
うむ　うずまきナルトの家じゃ。
This is Naruto Uzumaki's house.
四代目の忘れ形見。
Lord Fourth's orphan.
あの子が下忍に。
So that child is a genin.
ハハッ　少しは興味を
持ったようじゃの。
Are you a little interested now?
（カカシ）ここがナルトの家ね。
So this is where Naruto lives.
そうだ。
Yes.
《この牛乳
かなり賞味期限が過ぎている》
This milk is way past
its expiration date.
《あのきっちりした
ミナト先生の子供とは思えないな》
Minato Sensei was so meticulous.
I can't believe this is his son.
マヌケなやつだが→
He's a bit of a fool,
お前に見張らせるのがいちばんだ。
but it would be best if
you looked after him.
お前は鼻がきく。
You have good instincts.
それから　お前の班には例の
うちは一族のサスケもいるぞ。
That Uchiha boy, Sasuke, is
also on your squad.
健闘を祈る。
I wish you the best of luck.
了解。
Understood.
《こりゃ
大変なことになりそうだ》
What have I gotten myself into?
次は　くのいちの…。
Next up is a kunoichi—
（メブキ）ようこそ　三代目様！
それにカカシ先生！
Welcome, Lord Third!
And Kakashi Sensei as well!
このたびは　うちのサクラが
お世話になります。
Our Sakura, will be under
your supervision!
どうぞ　どうぞ　中へ！
Come in and
have some tea!
（キザシ）チャチャっと茶でも
出しますんで！
I'll hurry and get it rea-tea!
なんちゃって。
やだ　もうあんたったら～！
I couldn't resist saying that!
Oh, stop! You're so silly!
オホン！　一応
おしのびで来ておるんでの。
I'm here unofficially.
生徒の家で
茶を呼ばれたとあっては→
So if I accept an invitation for tea
at a student's home,
他の生徒の親から
何を言われるか　わからんのじゃ。
other parents might frown upon it.
そんな　かたいことおっしゃらず！
Oh, please don't be so formal.
そうそう　みんな
火影様のおかげで→
Yes! Thanks to you,
we live in peace and have nothing
to worry about, Lord Hokage!
安心して暮らしてんだから
カゲで文句なんて言いやしませんよ。
No one would dare complain.
ささっ　カカシ先生も！
Please, you too, Kakashi Sensei!
娘の先生になる人なんだから
遠慮なさらないでね→
After all, you're going to be
our daughter's sensei.
ささっ　どうぞどうぞ！
So please come in!
《カカシ：こりゃ　ほんとに大変だ》
This is really not looking good...
最後は　うちはサスケの家じゃ。
The last up one is...
Sasuke Uchiha's house.
かつては　特別な自治区に
暮らしていた　うちはの一族も→
At one time, the Uchiha lived in
a special autonomous district.
今や　サスケ一人。
Now, only Sasuke remains...
ふむ　サスケの父　うちはフガクは
厳格な男だったからな→
Sasuke's father Fugaku Uchiha
was very strict.
しつけもよかったと見える。
Seems the boy is very disciplined.
兄のイタチも
きっちりとしていましたからね。
His older brother Itachi was
very meticulous as well.
ああ　そうじゃったな。
Yes, I remember.
イタチも　おぬしの下につけていたな。
I assigned him under you.
兄同様　よろしく頼むぞ。
Look after the younger one as well
父　フガクに代わって
わしからの願いじゃ。
I'm asking in place of
their father, Fugaku.
イタチには　教えることなんて
何ひとつありませんでしたよ。
I didn't have to teach Itachi a thing.
写輪眼にしても　俺以上の眼を
持っているようでしたし。
His Sharingan was far
more effective than mine.
とはいえ　木ノ葉で
写輪眼を持つのは→
Regardless, you are the only Leaf Shinobi
who possesses a Sharingan now.
今や　おぬしのみ。
サスケが写輪眼を開眼できるか
どうかは　わからぬが→
We don't know yet if Sasuke
will be able to activate his...
そのときには　おぬしが
サポートしてやってくれ。
はぁ。
but if he does,
you must be there for him.
Yes...
((オビト　お前。
Obito, you—!
(（オビト）ここは…　仲間は俺が守る))
This is where...
I'll protect my friends!
《オビト…》
Obito...
((リン：カカシ…))
Kakashi...
《リン…》
Rin...
この眼には
悲劇がつきまといます。
The shadow of tragedy
trails this eye.
できれば
写輪眼など開眼しないで→
It might be best not to activate
the Sharingan at all.
終わるほうが
いいのかもしれません。
ですが…。
But...
ですが　よくも悪くも→
But for better or for worse,
この眼には
友が　仲間への思いが→
this eye holds a key into how
I feel about my comrades.
重要なカギを持つようです。
悲劇を引き起こすのが
思いの裏返しと考えれば→
If one thinks that there is a downside
to having these kinds of feelings...
that it attracts tragedy...
そうはならぬよう
仲間を大切に思う気持を→
then I must see to it that
they treasure their comrades,
見極める必要があります。
in order to prevent that
from happening.
ああ　今年も→
おぬしの審査基準は
変わらぬようじゃな。
It seems your judging criteria
remains unchanged this year.
《しかし　ナルトとは
対照的な部屋だな》
Still...
This room is quite a contrast
from Naruto's.
なぜなんです？
何がじゃ。
Why?
Why what?
なぜ　あの３人を
俺の担当にしたんです？
Why did you put me in charge
of those three?
確かに　ドジな落ちこぼれに
優秀なエリート→
Well, there's a hopeless fool,
a skilled protégé and a clever kunoichi...
そして　賢い　くのいち。
かつてのミナト班のようじゃな。
あっ。
I'd say it's much like
Minato's old team.
そ　それでは　わざと俺に。
S-So you chose me on purpose?!
カカシよ　わしも火影じゃ。
Listen Kakashi, I am the Hokage.
個人的な思惑で
人事を決めたりはせん。
I would never base
my personnel decisions
on personal preference!
適材適所　人材の配置には→
It's all about the right man
for the right job...
I carefully consider each of
these assignments...
頭を悩ませておる。
アカデミーの教師が
どう思っているかは別としてな。
Separately from what the teachers
at the Academy believe.
((イルカ：サスケとナルトを同じ班に。
Sasuke and Naruto will be
on the same squad?
なるほど
サスケは　卒業生２７名中　一番の成績。
That's brilliant!
Sasuke graduated at the top of
his class out of 27 students...
対してナルトは　最下位。
Whereas Naruto was last in class.
(班のバランスをとった
ということですね))
It seems you did that to keep
the squad balanced!
今や　忍も集団行動。
These are times when
a squad's composition greatly affects
班編成が任務の成功率を
大きく左右する。
shinobi and their actions,
and subsequently, their success rate.
ゆえに専門班のバリエーションを
持つことが→
It is the duty of those who govern
to maintain special teams that
possess a variety of skills.
里を治める者の責務となる。
例えば　昨年　編成したガイ班。
For example, Guy's team that
was formed last year.
アカデミーの教師が言うような
バランスではなく→
It certainly doesn't
have the kind of balance
the instructors at
the Academy recommend.
体術に大きく特化した
班編成じゃろう？
It's a squad that specializes largely
in taijutsu.
確かに。
今年は　更に索敵に特化した班。
You're right.
This year, they have really
come into their own.
秘伝忍術による　戦術特化班なども
編成するつもりじゃ。
I also intend to organize
specialty military squads
that utilize Secret Ninjutsu.
そういう意味では
ナルトは　九尾の人柱力だし→
From that perspective,
Naruto is the Jinchuriki
of the Nine Tails...
サスケも　うちはの写輪眼を
開眼する可能性を持っている。
and Sasuke has the potential
to activate the Sharingan...
さっきも言ったが
サスケの写輪眼をサポートできるのは→
As I mentioned earlier,
you are the only one who can
advise Sasuke with his Sharingan.
おぬししか　おらんからな。
《先を考えれば→
Looking ahead, it is imperative
サスケには九尾をコントロールできる→
that Sasuke awaken his Sharingan
that can control the Nine Tails...
写輪眼を
開眼してもらわねばならん。
あの夜の悲劇を
繰り返さぬためにも》
That night's tragedy
must never happen again.
２人が特殊なのは
わかりましたが→
I understand that those two are special.
あのサクラという女の子は？
But what about the girl Sakura?
ん？　さて→
よい　くのいちとなる素質は
あると思うが→
Well, I believe she has
the potential to be a good kunoichi.
今のところは　普通じゃのう。
Right now, she's average. However...
じゃがな…。
((大蛇丸：手裏剣影分身の術。
Shuriken Shadow Clone Jutsu!
《ほう　こやつ→
He's already picked up
one of my jutsu!
わしの技を　もう盗みおったか》
（綱手）やるな　大蛇丸。
Good one, Orochimaru!
（自来也）ん～　俺だって。
I can do that too!
何　自来也までか？
What? You too, Jiraiya?
へぇ。
(しゅ　手裏剣　ありったけの術))
Shu... Shuriken...
Whatever Jutsu...!
才能は　人を引きつけ→
Talent attracts people...
男は　女を意識し→
Men notice women...
競争は
互いを成長させていくのじゃ。
And rivalry matures both...
So they say.
頑張れ。
いけ～！
Go get 'em!
Do it!
つまり　班の成長も
考慮にいれていると？
So you've even considered how
the squad will develop?
そういうことじゃ。
That's right.
《カカシ：確かに　オビトも→
Without a doubt...
リンに認められようと必死だった。
Obito was desperate for Rin
to acknowledge him.
でも…》
But...
三代目の考えは　わかりました。
I understand your logic
behind this Lord Third.
しかし　自分は二度も→
But... I failed twice with squads
that you organized.
三代目が考える班編成に
失敗した男です。
やはり　自分には担当上忍なんて
向いていないとしか。
I don't think I'm cut out
to be a jonin leader.
個人的感情で落第させたのか？
いいえ。
Did you fail them because of
your own personal feelings?
No...
うむ…　彼らには悪いことをしたが
厳しい忍の世界じゃ→
It was unfortunate for them.
But this is the strict world of shinobi.
若いうちに気づいておいたほうが
よいこともある。
It's better that they learn this
when they're young.
結果的に　彼らの人生には
重要だったはずじゃ。
Ultimately, this will prove to be
a valuable lesson for them.
ですが　それはたまたま
結果オーライだっただけでは…。
But it wasn't planned.
It just happened to work out.
そうかもしれん。　が　わしは
そうなると信じたのじゃ。
Perhaps.
But I had faith that
it would work out.
信じて　おぬしに託したのじゃ。
I trusted you.
（カカシ）三代目…。
Lord Hiruzen...
ミナトもそうじゃった。
It was the same with Minato too.
（カカシ）えっ　ミナト先生が！？
Minato Sensei?
((うむ…
演習の報告書だけ見ると→
Judging from only
the practice reports,
カカシの独断専行と
とれなくもないが。
it would seem that
Kakashi acted arbitrarily.
（ミナト）カカシの力量や才覚は
卒業生の中ではズバ抜けています。
Kakashi is leagues ahead
of the other graduates
in terms of skill and intelligence.
そして　これからの成長も
楽しみな下忍です。
It's exciting just thinking about
this genin's development.
確かに
サクモさんのこともあってか→
Perhaps due to the incident
with Sakumo, he's very headstrong.
いこじになるところも
ありますが→
すぐにチームワークの重要性に気づくと
私は信じています。
But I have faith that he'll realize
the importance of teamwork.
信じるか…　うむ　そうじゃのう。
Faith, huh?
Yes, you're right.
(では　そう信じるおぬしを
わしは信じようかの))
I shall have faith in your faith.
《ミナト先生は気づいていた…
俺の　浅はかな作戦に。
Minato Sensei knew all along
about my selfish and
shallow strategy.
それでも　俺がいつか
気づくと信じて》
But he had faith that one day,
I would realize it...
弟子を信じて見守る
これもまた　師のありかたじゃ。
To believe in one's student
and to watch over them...
is also part of being a teacher.
《父さん　俺は　父さんを否定する
ような生き方をしてしまった》
Father... I spent my life denying you...
((オビト：俺は　白い牙を
本当の英雄だと思ってる。
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero.
（オビト）確かに　忍の世界で
ルールや掟を破るやつは→
Sure, in the world of Ninja,
one who breaks the rules and
regulations is regarded as trash.
クズ呼ばわりされる。　けどな→
But... those who abandon their comrades
are worse than trash!
(仲間を大切にしないやつは
それ以上のクズだ))
《けど　次の世代の子供たちには
あんな悲劇は→
But...
I can't repeat that tragedy again
with a new generation.
二度と起こさせるわけには
いかないんです》
（ナルト）あんたが　俺たちの先生か？
Are you going to be our Sensei?
俺は　うずまきナルト
火影になる男だってばよ！
I'm Naruto Uzumaki!
And I'm going to be the Hokage!
（アスマ）奈良シカマル　秋道チョウジ
山中いの。
Shikamaru Nara, Choji Akimichi,
Ino Yamanaka!
（３人）はい！
（アスマ）俺が　お前たちの班の→
- Yes, sir!
I'm the jonin leader of
your squad, Asuma Sarutobi.
担当上忍となる　猿飛アスマだ。
早速　ミーティングに入る　いくぞ！
（３人）あ…。
We're going to have a meeting now.
Follow me.
（シカマル）じゃあな。
（チョウジ）お先！
See ya!
So long!
（いの）サスケ君　またね！
See you again, Sasuke!
（サクラ）さっさと行け！　イノブタ！
Get lost, Ino Pig!
なんだ　シカマルたちの先生かよ。
What? He's their sensei?
次こそ　俺たちの先生が
来るってばよ！
Well, the next one will be ours!
（キバ）いいや　俺たちの先生に
決まってるぜ！
Nope, it'll be our sensei next!
な？　赤丸。
（赤丸）ワンワン！
Right, Akamaru?
（紅）犬塚キバ　油女シノ　日向ヒナタ。
Kiba Inuzuka, Shino Aburame,
Hinata Hyuga...
（紅）あなたたちの担当となった
夕日紅よ。　よろしくね。
I'm Yuhi Kurenai and
I'll be your leader.
Nice to meet you all.
ヘヘ～　ドベのいる班の先生は
来るのもドベってな！
The loser squad gets
a loser sensei too!
（３人）遅い！
- He's late!
（カカシ）俺を待っているのか？　テンゾウ。
Have you been waiting for me, Tenzo?
（ヤマト）
テンゾウはやめてくださいよ　先輩。
Stop calling me "Tenzo," Senpai.
なら　先輩ってのも
もう違うだろ。
Then drop the "senpai."
（ヤマト）先輩は先輩ですよ。
暗部を辞めたからって→
You'll always be my senpai.
That will never change,
even if you're no longer ANBU.
そこに変わりはないんですから。
で　何だ？　俺の抜けた穴をうめる
大活躍だと噂には聞いている。
So what do you want?
I've heard the rumors
that it's been very difficult
trying to find my replacement.
下忍のおもりをやってる俺を
わざわざ笑いにでも来たのか？
Or did you come all this way
to laugh at me, the genin babysitter?
いいえ　あれから
ずいぶん経ったのに→
Not at all!
But that was such a long time ago.
先輩は変わらないなと。
You haven't changed a bit, Senpai.
悪いが　今日の俺は忙しいんだ。
Sorry, but I'm busy today.
お前の相手をしている暇はない。
I can't stand around and chat.
ハハハ…　とっくに
下忍との顔合わせの時間は→
It's way past the time you were
supposed to meet your genin.
過ぎてますけどね。
じゃ　またな。
Well, see you later.
またな…　ですか。
"See you later," huh?
Maybe he did change a little.
やっぱり少し変わったかな？
今と過去しか見ていなかった
先輩が　「また」とはね。
For someone who was fixated
on the past and present...
to hear him say,
"see you later..."
ヒヒッ。
《カカシ：ベタないたずらか。
A silly prank...
だが
いたずらもチームワークがあるなら》
Still, if this prank was
the result of teamwork...
キャハハッ
引っかかった　引っかかった。
He fell for it!
《カカシ：仕掛けたのはナルト》
So Naruto's the perp.
先生　ごめんなさい。
私はとめたんですが　ナルト君が…。
I'm so sorry, Sensei.
I tried to stop him, but Naruto...
《カカシ：サクラは言い訳。　自身の保身。
Sakura makes excuses and
tries to protect herself...
サスケは我関せず。　仲間とすら
思っていないようだな。
Sasuke minds his own business...
He probably doesn't consider them
as comrades.
チームワークのかけらもなし…　か》
There's not even a shred of teamwork...
ここに鈴が２つある。
There are two bells here.
これを俺から昼までに
奪い取ることが課題だ。
Your task is to take these bells away
from me by noon.
もし　昼までに俺から
鈴を奪えなかったやつは昼飯抜き。
The one who fails to take
a bell gets no lunch.
《仲間割れを誘うために
仕組んだ演習内容だ。
This exercise is to try
to split the team.
気づいてくれよ》
I hope you figure it out.
鈴を取れないやつは
任務失敗ってことで失格だ。
And failing the exercise means
failing the mission.
つまり　この中で最低でも１人は→
In order words, at the very least,
one of you will be returning
to the Academy.
アカデミーへ
戻ってもらうことになるわけだ。
じゃあ始めるぞ。　よ～い　スタート。
Let's get started.
Ready... Start!
《教室のいたずらの様子じゃ→
Considering the prank
in the classroom...
チームワークで攻めてくるとは
思えないが》
I doubt if they'll work
as a team to attack me.
うぉ…！
《やはり…　か》
I knew it.
お前ら　最後にもう一度だけ
チャンスをやる。
Well, guys!
I'm going to give you
one more chance.
ただし　昼からはもっと過酷な
鈴取り合戦だ。
However, the afternoon scramble
for the bells will be much more difficult.
挑戦したいやつだけ弁当を食え。
If you accept the challenge,
eat your lunch.
ただし　ナルトには食わせるな。
え？
However, don't let Naruto eat.
ルールを破って
ひとり昼飯　食おうとした罰だ。
Huh?
That's your punishment
for breaking the rule
and attempting to eat lunch alone.
もし食わせたりしたら　そいつを
その時点で試験失格にする。
If you give Naruto any food,
you will be
immediately disqualified.
ここでは俺がルールだ。　わかったな。
I am the law here.
Understand?
《ミナト先生が
俺を信じてくれたように→
Minato Sensei had faith in me...
俺もお前たちを信じるべきなのか。
So should I have faith in them too?
だが　その判断そのものが
ブレているとしたら…》
But what if I'm wrong
to begin with?
((オビト：てめえは
心の優しさってもんがねえのか？
Don't you have any kindness
in your heart?
(いつもルールだ　掟だ
うっせえんだよ))
All you ever think about are
rules, rules, rules! It's annoying!
《そうだよな。　俺はいまだに→
That's right.
自分の作ったルールに
従おうとしている》
I'm still trying to stick to my rules...
((さっさと行こうぜ
隊長さんよ))
Come on, let's go, Captain.
《カカシ：オビト　お前はチームのために→
Obito...
For the sake of the team,
you walked over to me that day...
自分から歩み寄って
くれたんだったよな。
あの時　もっとお前の仲間を思う
気持をくめていれば…。
If only I had accepted
the friendship you extended...
その小さなサインを
大切にしていれば…》
If I had embraced
that little sign you gave me...
（サスケ）ほらよ。
Here.
《オビト　見えているか？
Obito, did you see that?
お前やリンのこと
俺は一生忘れることはない》
I'll never forget you or Rin.
((カカシ。
カカシ。
Kakashi.
(カカシ))
お前ら！
キャッ！
You!
合格。
Pass.
《だが　それでも俺は
新しい仲間とともに→
But I think I'm going to move forward
with some new comrades.
前に進もうと思うよ。
ナルト　サスケ　サクラ
俺はお前たちを信じる。
Naruto, Sasuke, Sakura...
I'm going to believe in you.
そして　オビト　リン…
お前たちに約束しよう。
And Obito, Rin...
I'll make a promise.
信じる仲間たちを
俺は絶対に死なせない》
I'll believe in my comrades
and I'll never let them die!
これにて演習　終わり。　全員合格。
That ends the survival exercise.
You all pass.
第７班は明日より任務開始だ。
Squad Seven will start
its mission tomorrow!
えっ！　縄ほどけ！
Huh?! Hey, untie me!
kidzuite ndaro sou sekai ga kataru itsuwari to
I'm sure you've realized by now that the world tells lies
amai wana ni soko ni wa hontou nante nai koto o
And lays alluring traps, but there's no truth behind them
riyuu sagashite run away why? sono mewotojiteru no?
Search for a reason Run away Why?
Why are you closing your eyes?
tell me why can't you
Tell me why can't you
shinjitsu ni te o nobase!
Reach out for the truth!
always (sakebe shout out) all time (tsukame catch up)
Always (Scream, Shout out)
All the time (Catch it, Catch up)
everybody knows (we are the seeker get fire!!!)
Everybody knows (We are the seeker Get fire!!!)
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
tsuyoku aritai to negau nonaraba
if you firmly wish for it
narase narase mezame no kane o
Ring, ring the bell of awakening
koyoi tsuki no shita de kokoro sakebe
Shout from your heart under the moon tonight
utae utae hoero hoero
Sing, sing, howl, howl,
kibou no hikari o nozomu nonaraba
if you want the light of hope
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
akai tsuki no shita de kimi o sakebe
Shout to you under the red moon
ima ima ima flame up (catch the fire)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Catch the fire)
ima ima ima flame up (blaze up!!!)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Blaze up!!!)
I couldn't keep my promise
to you.
I'm trash. But you're a hero
of the Leaf.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
You don't have
to become trash too!
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Obito, your once strong will
is still alive today, right next to me!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
What the current me can do is...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Kakashi's Resolve."
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華な
歌手の皆さんによる→
... protect the current Naruto!
華麗なステージをお届けいたします。